Guide to the Earle Gister, Associate Dean of Academic Affairs and Chair of the Department of Acting, Yale School of Drama, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Earle Gister, associate dean of academic affairs and chair of the Department of Acting, Yale School of Drama, records
1978-1998
RU 847
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.25
(8 boxes)
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, commencement files, and acting scene presentations documenting the activities and initiatives of Earle Gister as associate dean of academic affairs and chair of the Department of Acting in the Yale School of Drama.
Yale School of Drama
Gister, Earle R., 1934-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 22-B (YRG 22-B), Records of the deputy, associate, and assistant deans of the Yale School of Drama.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of subject files, correspondence, commencement files, and acting scene presentations documenting the activities and initiatives of Earle Gister as associate dean of academic affairs and chair of the Department of Acting in the Yale School of Drama.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Acting -- Study and teaching; Deans (Education); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale School of Drama; Yale School of Drama. Dept. of Acting; Yale University -- Administration
- Subject files, correspondence, commencement files, and acting scene presentations of Earle Gister, 1978-1998; Accession 2001-A-013
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2034.
  - School of Drama- General Commencement files, 1979-1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and recommendations inalldepartments, arranged alphabetically, Circa 1980-1999 (Box 1)
  - Acting
  - Scene Presentations, 1988-1997 (Box 2)
  - League of Professional Theatre Training Programs file (19 folders), 1980-1997 (Box 2)
  - Subject files
    - Alliance Resident Theatres, NY (Box 2)
    - Alumni Day, 1980 (Box 2)
    - American Shakespeare Theatre, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Asolo, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Awards and Fellowships, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Bermuda, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Cabaret, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Career Day, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Circle Repertory Company (Box 2)
    - Council of Graduate Schools, 1990 (Box 2)
    - DavenportCollege, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Drama Alumni Executive Committee, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Drama Library Guide (Box 2)
    - Educational Testing Service, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Ensemble Company for the Performing Arts, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Ensemble Studio Theater, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Institute for Movement Exploration, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Interns, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
    - Internships, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Kamarack Preparations, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Kellogg National Fellowship Program, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Kesselring Awards, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
    - Labor Institute for Human Enrichment, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Lasagouine, press release, 1980 (Box 2)
    - LeonardDavis Centerfor the Performing Arts (Box 2)
    - Living Theater (Box 2)
    - Living Stage Theatre Co., 1984 (Box 2)
    - Management Consultants for the Arts, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Mime Ensemble of Canada (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Museum of American Theatre, letter, 1984 (Box 3)
    - NEA, letter from Brad Davis re: possible proposals, 1980 (Box 3)
    - NEA Artistic Director Internship Program, Report by L. Richards and memo, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
    - National Foundation for Advancement in the Arts (Box 3)
    - New Directors Project, 1984 (Box 3)
    - New England Theatre Conference, 1987 (Box 3)
    - New York Theatre Workshop, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Office of Community and State Relations, letter re: YSD/YRT involve. in N. Haven, 1984 (Box 3)
    - O'Neil Theatre Center, letter, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Pasadena Playhouse, letter, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Paycheck receipts (legal pad pages with signatures), 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Personnel Activity Reporting, University memo, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Police Departments, complaints, request, action, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Physical Plant issues, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
    - Playwriting awards, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Present Stage - The Actor's Space, etter from L. Richards, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Priority work/rehearsal times, Gister memo to YSD (Box 3)
    - Production Management memo, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Prospective Students, letters, 1980 (Box 3)
    - PTM Seminars, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Readinglists, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations, for students and interns (from J. Miller and E. Gister), 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Red, Virginia S., letter to E. Gister, 1984 (Box 3)
    - REFCOM Visual Communications, letters, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Richards, Lloyd, 1misc. correspondence, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Roy Hart Theatre/R. Armstrong, letter and info., 1984 (Box 3)
    - Russian and East European Studies, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Schiller College Europe, letters, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - Screen Actors Guild, letters, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Seminar Proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - ShorelineSchoolfor Art and Music, flyer, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Sound Concepts Inc., 1980 (Box 3)
    - Space Allocation, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Squat Theatre, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Student Discretionary Awards, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Student Memos, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Student academic matters, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Student Warnings, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Student Correspondence, memos and letters, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Summer Newsletter, 1979 (Box 3)
    - TCG's Artist Bulletin (Theatre Communications Group) (Box 3)
    - TCG National Auditions, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - The Arts/The Workplace Project, Arts Council of Greater New Haven, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Theatre of LatinAmerica, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Theatre Studies Advisory Committee, 1980-1986 (Box 3)
    - University Tribunal, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Valley Railroad proposal (Box 3)
    - Visiting Groups (2 folders), 1979-1984 (Box 3)
    - Visitors, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    - Actors in residency (Box 3)
    - New England Theater Conference (Box 3)
    - Visitors (Box 3)
    - Welcoming Address, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
    - Yale China Association, Annual Report; E. Gister letters; Huang Zolin, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
    - Yale Drama Alumni Executive Committee, minutes of meeting, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Yale Liaison Program, memo from Provost George May, 1981 (Box 3)
    - YSD Publicity, copy of Delta Airline's Sky Magazine with article re:Drama in Universitiesincludes quote by E. Gister, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Casting files, 2 binders, 1982-1990 (Box 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence
  - 1980-1983 (Box 4)
    - 1983-1988 (Box 5)
    - 1989-1991 (Box 6)
    - 1991-1994 (Box 8)
    - 1994-1998 (Box 7)